Guide to the Leslie Cagan Papers TAM.138
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Subject Files Accessioned 1993-2014
  - NCPME: Pennsylvania: General, 1990-1991 (Box 32, Folder 100)
  - National Campaign for Peace in the Middle East (NCPME): Erie, Pennsylvania, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - NCPME: Langhorne, Pennsylvania, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - NCPME: New Cumberland, Pennsylvania, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - NCPME: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - NCPME: Pittsburg, Pennsylvania, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - NCPME: Providence, Rhode Island, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - NCPME: Watertown, South Dakota, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - NCPME: Knoxville, Tennessee, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - NCPME: Maryville, Tennessee, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - NCPME: Nashville, Tennessee, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - NCPME: Austin, Texas, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - NCPME: Dallas, Texas, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - NCPME: Houston, Texas, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - NCPME: Johnson City, Texas, Undated (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - NCPME: San Marcos, Texas, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - NCPME: New Braufels, Texas, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - NCPME: Salt Lake City, Utah, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - NCPME: Virginia: General, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - NCPME: Pullman, Washington, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - NCPME: Seattle, Washington, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - NCPME: Spokane, Washington, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - NCPME: Tacoma, Washington, Undated (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - NCPME: Athens, West Virginia, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - NCPME: Charleston, West Virginia, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - NCPME: Lewisburg, West Virginia, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - NCPME: Bayfield City, Wisconsin, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - NCPME: Madison, Wisconsin, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - NCPME: Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - NCPME: Laramie, Wyoming, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 29)
  - NCPME: Other Cities, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - NCPME: New York City Contacts List, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - NCPME: Phone Scripts, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 32)
  - NCPME: February 4, 1991 NYC Organizing Meeting Sign-in Sheets (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - NCPME: Volunteer Lists, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 34)
  - NCPME: Banners, Artwork, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 35)
  - NCPME: Volunteer Activity Sheets, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 36)
  - NCPME: Leafleting, Lists, Maps, etc., [1990-1991] (Box 33, Folder 37)
  - NCPME: Lobbying, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 38)
  - NCPME: Emergency Demos, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 39)
  - NCPME: Bronx Organizing, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 40)
  - NCPME: Manhattan Organizing, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 41)
  - NCPME: Brooklyn Organizing, [1991] (Box 33, Folder 42)
  - NCPME: Campaign: General, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 43)
  - NCPME: Campaign: Outreach, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 44)
  - NCPME: Peacekeepers, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 45)
  - NCPME: New York Campaign, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 46)
  - NCPME: New York Media, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 47)
  - NCPME: Fundraising: Art World List, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 48)
  - NCPME: Transportation Ticket Sellers Sheets, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 49)
  - NCPME: Bus Lists, NYC, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 50)
  - NCPME: Press Lists, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 51)
  - NCPME: Newspaper Clippings, Prior to January 26, 1991 Demonstration (Box 33, Folder 52)
  - NCPME: Newspaper Clippings, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 53)
  - NCPME: Captain Yolanda Huet-Vaughn, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 54)
  - NCPME: Public Relations: Letters, Human Contact, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 55)
  - NCPME: General, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 56)
  - NCPME: Organizational Endorsements for January 26, 1991 Demonstration (Box 33, Folder 57)
  - NCPME: Religious Letter, [1991] (Box 33, Folder 58)
  - NCPME: "Iraq and Palestine: Bush's Double Standard on Occupation" (Flyer), Undated (Box 33, Folder 59)
  - NCPME: Educational Mailings, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 60)
  - NCPME: "Crisis in the Gulf: An Historical Overview", Undated (Box 33, Folder 61)
  - NCPME: Educational Materials (Articles), 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 62)
  - NCPME: "ACCESS Guide to the Persian Gulf Crisis", 1991 (Box 33, Folder 63)
  - American Friends Service Committee (AFSC): Peace Education and Women's Program, 1980-1984 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Boston Area Socialist-Feminist Organization: FBI and Grand Jury Defensive strategizing and organizing, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - War Conference, The, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - National Mobilization for Justice and Peace in Central America and Southern Africa, 1987 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - National Mobilization for Justice and Peace in Central America and Southern Africa: Right Wing Attacks on, 1987 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Women's School (Boston, MA), 1971-1976 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Women's School (Boston, MA): Socialist Feminism course, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Women's School (Boston, MA): Courses and general, 1974; undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Boudin, Kathy; Cointelpro; the Anti-Springbok Five; Judy Clark; Weather Underground, 1975; 1981-1985 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Redwood Cultural Work, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Redwood Cultural Work, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Redwood Cultural Work, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Redwood Cultural Work, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Susan Saxe Defense Committee, 1978-1981 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Study/Working Group on Electoral Democracy: Conference, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Speaking Tour, 1982-1983 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Housing (New York City), 1989-1990 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Save our Cities! Save Our Children! March on Washington: Publicity and organizing, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Save our Cities! Save Our Children! March on Washington: Endorsements/Mobilizing, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Save our Cities! Save Our Children! March on Washington: Publicity and organizing, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Save our Cities! Save Our Children! March on Washington: Program, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Save our Cities! Save Our Children! March on Washington: Logistics and Bus Parking (Baltimore), 1992 (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Save our Cities! Save Our Children! March on Washington: Materials from different cities, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Save our Cities! Save Our Children! March on Washington: Publicity and Public Service Announcement, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Mothers March Against AIDS, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Common Agenda Coalition, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - Palestine Solidarity Committee, 1990-1994 (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - Arab-American Institute and Counter-Terrorism Bill, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - "In Our Hands" June 12, 1983 film and event commemorating June 12, 1982 March for Peace, Jobs, and Justice (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Right-Wing Attack on Disarmament Movement, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Speak Out! (Speakers' Bureau), 1990-1991 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - El Salvador: Background, assorted actions, etc., 1989 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - El Salvador: Emergency Meeting, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Reproductive/Abortion Rights Fight, 1989-1990 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - War Resisters League: Conference on Feminism and Militarism, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Anti-nuclear and disarmament movement: Brochures from groups, Early 1980s (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Anti-nuclear and disarmament movement: Articles and clippings, Early 1980s (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Feminism and the anti-nuclear movement: Articles and clippings, Early 1980s (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Coalition for a Nuclear Weapons Freeze, Early 1980s (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - American Friends Service Committee women and militarism packet, 1981-1982 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Women and militarism: Articles, Early 1980s (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Vietnam: Clipping, leaflet, and handwritten essay on Vietnamese women, 1974; undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Economic Conversion Strategy Conference, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - MFS: Deadly Connections Information Packet, Undated (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Institute for New Communications and Women's Education Institute: Women's Economic Roundtable, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Central America: Articles, pamphlets, and typescript of notes form a workshop-meeting in Connorsville, October 1983, Early 1980s (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - American Friends Service Committee (AFSC): Articles on women and militarism, 1980-1981 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Iran/Contra Scandal: Response, 1986-1987 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - ProPeace/Great March for Survival, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - Readings from "Deadly Connections" Conference (AFSC), 1982 (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Materials from "Deadly Connections" Conference (AFSC), 1982 (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - Women's Pentagon Action, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - Research material for anti-draft article, Undated (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - Women's Peace Encampment, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - Indochina Aid and Friendship Project, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 28)
  - Middle East: Articles and pamphlets, Mid-1980s (Box 35, Folder 29)
  - Middle East: Articles and pamphlets, Mid-1980s (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - Not in a folder: Computer disks and unidentified notes, Undated (Box 35)
  - Movement: Nukes, disarmament, etc., 1982; undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Assorted New Right material, Early 1980s (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - National Anti-Klan Network, Early 1980s (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Peace and disarmament, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Nuclear power, 1978-1979; undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Nuclear Reactions and Nuclear Times, 1982-1983 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Gay activism, 1988-1990 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Middle East Peace Network, 1989; undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Middle East Peace Action Network, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Peace Dividend (Organizing), 1990 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Peace Dividend: NYC, 1990 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - New Alliance Party, 1988-1990 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Domestic Partnership, 1992-1993; undated (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Domestic Partnership, 1990-1993 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - CUNY Is Our Future Coalition: Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - CUNY Is Our Future Coalition: Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - CUNY Is Our Future Coalition: Organizing, 1998-1999 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - CUNY Is Our Future Coalition: Meeting agenda, notes, etc., 1998-1999 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - CUNY Is Our Future Coalition: Correspondence and leaflets, 1998-1999 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - CUNY: Board of Trustees, 1998-1999 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - CUNY: Board of Regents, 1999 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - CUNY: Legal/Lawsuit?, 1998 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - CUNY: Information from other groups: Labor; SLAM; Community College Conference; Five Boroughs Institute, 1998-1999 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - CUNY Is Our Future Coalition: Effort to remove Badillo, 1999 (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - CUNY Is Our Future Coalition: Income; deposits, 1998-2000 (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - CUNY Is Our Future Coalition: Bills paid, 1998-1999 (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - CUNY: Newspaper clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - CUNY Is Our Future Coalition: Special projects, money, 1998 (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - CUNY Is Our Future Coalition: Financial papers, 1998 (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - CUNY: Background, 1997-2000 (Box 36, Folder 30)
  - CUNY: Schmidt Commission (Mayor's Advisory Task Force on CUNY), 1998-1999 (Box 36, Folder 31)
  - CUNY: Ford Foundation Remediation Study, 1998 (Box 36, Folder 32)
  - CUNY: High School Campaign: New Youth Connections mailing list, 1998 (Box 36, Folder 33)
  - Not in folders: CUNY Is Our Future Coalition leaflets; articles and circulars on CUNY, 1998-1999 (Box 36)
  - Margarita Lopez Campaign, 1997-1998 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - National Coalition for Peace and Justice, 1997-2000 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Left Unity Project, 1995-1997 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Collective Dialogue, 1990-1992 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Socialist Dialogue, 1989-1991 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Independent Progressive Politics Network (IPPN); National Committee for Independent Political Action (NCuba Information ProjectA), 1997-2000 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - NCuba Information ProjectA; Independent Politics Summit, 1996-1998 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - NCuba Information ProjectA, 1992-1994 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Campaign for People's Progressive Convention, 1992-1995 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - NCuba Information ProjectA, 1991-1992 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - NCuba Information ProjectA, 1989-1990 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - NCuba Information ProjectA: Where We Are, Where Do We Go From Here: Draft Political Statement, Undated (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Third Party Initiatives: Correspondence with and documents from the Wisconsin Network for Peace and Justice, the Labor Party Advocates, the New Party, the "Third Force" Conference, the Labor-Farm Party of Wisconsin, and Green Party USA., 1990-1992 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Other "Unity" Initiatives, 1991-1992 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - What Next? Third Party? Exploratory Committee, 1989-1991 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Unity Party, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Boston Initiative, 1992-1993 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Boston Initiative: Lists, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Majority Coalition for a New NY, 1991-1992 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Majority Coalition for a New NY, 1992-1993 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Majority Coalition for a New NY: Platform, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Mobilization for Survival (Boston): Federal Election Commission case (1), 1989- (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Mobilization for Survival (Boston): Federal Election Commission case (2), 1989- (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Break the Contract on America; Center for Constitutional Rights, 1995-1997 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Contract on America: Informational pieces, 1994-1995 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Rainbow Coalition: Contract on America Materials, 1994-1995 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Civilian Complaint Review Board; City-Wide Coalition to End Police Brutality, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Civilian Complaint Review Board (9/16/1992 Event), 1991-1992 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Sao Paolo Foro (Social Forum), Jul 1996 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Veterans Education Project, Jul 1992 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Working Group on Electoral Democracy, 1995 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - International women's Day Demonstration, Mar 1992 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Media and Democracy Congress, New York City, Oct 1997 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Pacifica Radio Internal Struggle: A-FCC, c.2000-c.2005 (Box 39)
  - Pacifica Radio Internal Struggle: Fi-Litigation, c.2000-c.2005 (Box 40)
  - Pacifica Radio Internal Struggle: Lo-Pacifica, c.2000-c.2005 (Box 41)
  - Pacifica Radio Internal Struggle: Pacifica-WPFW, c.2000-c.2005 (Box 42, Box 54, Box 55, Box 56)
  - Lesbian and Gay Movement (box 1). Includes: Ad Hoc Committee for an Open Process, 1999-2000, 19 folders and assorted papers; Dialogues on the Lesbian/Gay Left #1, 4/93, #2, 7/95, 7 folders; Lesbians and Gays for Dinkins, 1993 – 1 folder; Deborah Glick NYS Assembly Campaign, 1990 – 1 folder; Lesbian/Gay Prid March on Washingon, Oct., 1987 – 1 folder; Int'l Assn. of Lesbian/Gay Pride Coordinators, NYC Conference, Cot., 1997 – 1 folder; OUT Fund, 4/1990—6/1993 – 1 folder., 1993-2000 (Box 43)
  - Anti-Guiliani 1997 – 1 folder; Response to Amadou Diallo murder, Spring 1999 – 3 folders; Summit re: Police Brutality, April, 1999 – 1 folder; Direct Action Network of NYC, 1999 – 1 folder; Drop the Rock Campaign against Rockefeller Drug Laws, Spring, 2001 – 3 folders and a booklet; Conference in Colorado re: Iraq Work, Feb., 2001 – 1 folder; 9/11 Response/NYC Anti-War Network, etc., Fall, 2001 – 8 folders; Not in our Name – 1 folder; Committees of Correspondence for Democracy and Socialism, includes CofC Education Fund, National and NY CCDS, 1998-2009 – 26 folders; Assorted Papers., 1997-2009 (Box 44)
  - New York State Organizing, including materials from the Same Boat Coalition, budget struggles, NYC Council races, Mobilization to Save NY State., Undated (Box 45)
  - End of Vietnam War, 10th anniversary event, 1985 – 1 folder; End of Vietnam War, 25th anniversary event, 2000 – 4 folders, 1 envelope, information packet; Film about Vietnam, Regret to Inform, 1 folder, 1 packet; Republican National Convention protest, Philadelphia, 2000 – 10 folders, 1 packet; Independent Progressive Politics Network, assorted papers., 1985-2000, undated (Box 46)
  - CUBA: Venceramos Brigade, 1976 – 1 folder; World Youth Festival, Havana, 1978 – 1 folder; U.S.—Cuba Medical Project – 3 folders; National Network on Cuba – 1 folder; Assorted other folders and papers., 1976-1978, undated (Box 47)
  - UNITED FOR PEACE AND JUSTICE: Program work from Fall, 2002 to March, 2005 – 56 folders and assorted papers, 2002-2005 (Box 48)
  - UNITED FOR PEACE AND JUSTICE: Program work from May, 2005 to October, 2007 – 65 folders and assorted papers, 2005-2007 (Box 49)
  - UNITED FOR PEACE AND JUSTICE: National Assemblies (6/2003, 2/2005, 6, 2007, 12/2008) – 27 folders; Administrative and Steering Committee Meetings (7/2003-1/2009) and other items – 24 folders; Assorted items – 4 folders; Fund Raising – 8 folders., 2003-2009 (Box 50)
  - UNITED FOR PEACE AND JUSTICE: Program work from January 2008 to April 2009 – 18 folders and 2 envelopes; Office moves – 1 folder; Stack of assorted papers., 2008-2009, undated (Box 51)
  - Leslie Cagan Papers Accessioned Feb, 2011, 1970s-2000s [bulk 2000s] (Box 52)
    General
    Contains files on peace and social justice activism; notable organizations / issues represented include: WBAI/Pacifica Radio; Mobilization for Survival; United for Peace and Justice; CUNY Coalition; Abortion; Cuba; Housing; Nuclear Disarmament.
  - Buttons and Photographs of Iraqis, 2002-2006 (Box 53)
  - Posters, anti-nuclear arms race, 1982-1988 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Gulf War Protest photos, 1990-1991 (Box 53, Folder 2)